DILLON ROSE

Full Stack Engineer

📞 (954) 579-2558 @ DR@dillonmrose.com 🕜 linkedin.com/in/dillonmrose 🕜 dillonmrose.com 👂 Seattle

SUMMARY

I am a Full Stack Engineer with 10 years of experience specializing in building AI-powered user experiences. I have led the development of two projects from inception to over 1M monthly active users. I have a solid grasp of the processes and structures required to deliver new features, while ensuring live site reliability and maintaining code health. The expertise I gathered while working on Microsoft Copilot positions me to contribute significantly to any AI-powered experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React	Next.js	Python
C#	VSCode	Al Fluent

SOFT SKILLS

Technical documentation

Cross-Functional Collaboration

Cross-Org Communication

Security Best Practices

Data Governance

INTERESTS



Side projects



Guitar



Construction



Rock climbing

EXPERIENCE

Principal Software Engineer

Microsoft Copilot

- Shipped Microsoft Copilot on Teams, Outlook, Windows, Bing, Office.com and the standalone site serving ~7M daily active users
- \bullet Designed full stack solution for Turn 0 Prompt Suggestions which initiate ${\sim}3\%$ of sessions
- Designed and developed Teaching Moments feature serving 10+ tutorials to onboard users and upsell the paid feature set
- Reduced time from commit to production from 2 weeks to 3 days by rearchitecting the deployment strategy
- Serving as the Technical Lead for the Microsoft Copilot Client Platform team, responsible for reliability, user perceived latency, authentication, flighting, etc

Senior Software Engineer

Cortana

= 01/2017 - 01/2023

- Developed email search and composition capabilities for the initial launch of Cortana Invoke
- Incubated and scaled 'Play My Emails' feature to over 1M monthly active users
- Led team of 5 engineers through full rewrite of service powering 'Play My Emails' feature
- Improved user experience by designing custom audio streaming protocol for email readouts
- · Created variable playback speed feature based on feedback from user panels

Software Engineer II

Microsoft Maps

= 01/2016 - 01/2017

- Enhanced user experience by optimizing map icons displayed across multiple zoom levels on Bing Maps
- Developed Offline Search capabilities in the Windows Map app by rearchitecting Bing's online search stack
- Defined strategy for selecting which locations and businesses would be downloaded for offline search

Software Engineer

Bing

= 06/2014 - 01/2016

- Enhanced user satisfaction by optimizing a classifier and a ranker in Bing Local Search stack
- Reduced latency and business costs by developing rule-based classifier to serve head queries

ACHIEVEMENTS



Copilot for All

Expanded the Copilot user base by 10x by adding support for unlicensed business users and licensed consumer users. Projected to generate 80M new licenses and \$28 billion in annual revenue.



Knowledge Sharing Series

Led organization-wide learning series. Starting from the beginning of the development of Copilot to now, there have been 55 talks covering React basics, zustand, authentication, testability, performance, transformers, etc. I personally presented on VectorDBs, LangChain, scorecards and "The Effective Engineer" by Edmond Lau.

EDUCATION

Dual B.S. in Computer Science and Mathematical Sciences